<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>debian on Greycloak</title>
    <link>https://greycloak.com/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in debian on Greycloak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023, Vince Wadhwani; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 16:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greycloak.com/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install MariaDB in Debian Stretch</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-12-21-install-mariadb-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-12-21-install-mariadb-debian/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Note that this article for local installation of Maria DB or MySQL. It&#39;s intended to help you get up and running with the database locally and is not intended as a production tutorial. If you need to use either in a production environment, please contact a professional.
Step 1: update and install
1sudo apt update 2sudo apt upgrade 3sudo apt install mariadb-server mariadb-client Step 2: (Optional) Run the secure installation. Doesn&#39;t hurt to see the options for future reference.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up PostgreSQL on Debian Buster</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-07-debian-postgresql-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 03:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-07-debian-postgresql-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a previous article, we set up your Debian Buster system with git, ruby, and a bash shell that tells you the ruby version and branch. Next up, we&#39;re going to install PostgreSQL and dependencies needed to get it working with Ruby on Rails.
First, let&#39;s make sure your system is up to date:
1sudo apt update 2sudo apt upgrade Next, we&#39;re going to jump right in and install postgres 10:
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Debian Buster for Ruby Development</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-06-debian-ruby-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-06-debian-ruby-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So you&#39;ve got a new debian install and need to get it set up to do real work? Here&#39;s a quick guide to get the packages you need assuming you&#39;re using Debian&#39;s current testing distro, Buster, installed.
First, let&#39;s make sure your system is up to date:
1sudo apt update 2sudo apt upgrade Next, let&#39;s grab the essentials including git:
1sudo apt install git curl zlib1g-dev build-essential libssl-dev libreadline-dev libyaml-dev libsqlite3-dev sqlite3 libxml2-dev libxslt1-dev libcurl4-openssl-dev software-properties-common libffi-dev nodejs Before we get too far, let&#39;s configure git.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
