<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Greycloak</title>
    <link>https://greycloak.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Greycloak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023, Vince Wadhwani; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greycloak.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Headless SSD install on Raspberry Pi 4B</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2023-01-26-headless-ssd-install-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2023-01-26-headless-ssd-install-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I have a Raspberry Pi 4B that I use as a mini home server and pi-hole. I love that I can block intrusive ads, have a secure vpn connection to my home network, and have backup for my music collection. The Raspberry Pi 4 is a fun little device and if you can get your hands on one, it has a lot of cool uses. (Note, if you&#39;re having trouble, may I recommend RPILocator.. follow them on Mastadon for real time updates.)&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Dynamic DNS with Namecheap for Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-12-30-dynamic-dns-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-12-30-dynamic-dns-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve got a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.pi-hole.net/&#34;&gt;PiHole&lt;/a&gt; set up on my raspberry pi and have it connected to my home router. My ISP won&#39;t assign me a static IP address though it&#39;s pretty good about keeping the one I&#39;ve got active until I reboot my router. For the most part that&#39;s been good enough for me but I wanted to finally get dynamic dns going so I wouldn&#39;t have to worry about it again. There are some paid solutions out there and my router even supports a few of them by default. I&#39;m a cheapskate though and didn&#39;t want to have yet another subscription weighing me down. (Enough is enough!)&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Firefox address bar work like Chrome</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-11-19-firefox-address-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-11-19-firefox-address-bar/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using Firefox as my main browser for a few years now. I like supporting an independent organization and have come to really appreciate the containers functionality which helps me segragate activity. One gripe I&#39;ve had is that I much prefer the way Google Chrome handle&#39;s URL completion. When I&#39;m in Chrome and I type &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; it automatically autocompletes to &lt;code&gt;https://www.discord.com/app&lt;/code&gt; in the address bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, in Firefox typing the same thing autocompletes to &lt;code&gt;https://www.discord.com&lt;/code&gt; even if I&#39;ve got the full URL bookmarked and have the settings set to just look at my browsing history and bookmarks. It&#39;s be a small, but annoying problem for me.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joplin CLI on Raspberry Pi 4</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-08-05-joplin-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-08-05-joplin-cli/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been searching for a way to keep my notes and todos organized. Over the years I&#39;ve tried some interesting solutions like Evernote, Google Tasks, and even Task Warrior. All of them have their pros and cons but I&#39;ve recently really liked the flexibility and ease of use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screenshots will show you that it&#39;s got a complete Graphical User Interface and is usable across most operating systems including Linux so if you want to do that, by all means check it out. Installation is pretty straight forward and you won&#39;t need this guide.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you npm install globally?</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-22-should-you-npm-install-globally/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-22-should-you-npm-install-globally/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I was transitioning this blog from using Jekyll to Hexo. After comparing both, I feel I made the right choice. However, I almost started off on the wrong foot. Being unfamiliar with Node.js, I was reviewing the Hexo install instructions and the first thing it tells you is to install via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;npm install hexo-cli -g
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m running on Archlinux and got a permission denied error when I tried that. It&#39;s likely because I used pacman (the Archlinux package manager) to install node and/or npm. So that left me with the decision of whether to use sudo to force the install. After years of running homebrew, that felt like the wrong decision. And it is. Instead of using sudo, fix permissions or create a new directory. If in doubt, your problem is likely solved by creating a new, local directory.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting touchscreen events working with Firefox</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-01-firefox-with-touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-01-firefox-with-touch/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I bought this laptop with a touchscreen and occasionally find myself using it while surfing websites. Now with Chrome that worked just fine but with Firefox it tends to select areas of text instead of scrolling. That sucks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately it&#39;s quite fixable. You just have to modify the .desktop file (or launch from the command line) with an additional environmental option: &lt;code&gt;env MOZ_USE_XINPUT2=1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On most linux distributions, the .desktop file is in &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/share/applications&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;~/.local/share/applications&lt;/code&gt; but you can also modify it globally in &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/applications&lt;/code&gt; if you have root.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Archlinux Another Try</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-01-29-giving-arch-another-try/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-01-29-giving-arch-another-try/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I bought an HP Envy x360 a few months ago. It had the right combination of features I wanted. Touchscreen, 360 flip, smaller screen size, and decent graphics chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was I wanted to draw, read, and play games on a computer while running linux. Shouldn&#39;t be that hard to do but surpringly, any computers that have a touch screen and can flip are either too big to read on comfortably or have a lousy intel chip.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install MariaDB in Debian Stretch</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-12-21-install-mariadb-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-12-21-install-mariadb-debian/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Note that this article for local installation of Maria DB or MySQL. It&#39;s intended to help you get up and running with the database locally and is not intended as a production tutorial. If you need to use either in a production environment, please contact a professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1: update and install&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo apt update
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo apt upgrade
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo apt install mariadb-server mariadb-client
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Step 2: (Optional) Run the secure installation. Doesn&#39;t hurt to see the options for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patch the Ubuntu Kernel</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-11-01-patch-ubuntu-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-11-01-patch-ubuntu-kernel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I bought an HP Envy x360 and out of the box it works pretty well with linux. I&#39;ve got Ubuntu 18.10 installed and have only had to tweak a couple of minor things. There is however, one big problem and that is the touch screen doesn&#39;t work. It might be the HP firmware (I am still figuring out how to update it in linux) but in the meantime, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugzilla.kernel.org/show_bug.cgi?id=198715#c14&#34;&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; available. The question is how do we apply it? Let&#39;s find out.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Occasional Freezing on the HP Envy X360</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-31-fix-freezing-envyx360/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 10:09:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-31-fix-freezing-envyx360/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;01/2019 update: This doesn&#39;t seem to be necessary with the 4.20 kernel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently bought an HP Envy x360 13&amp;quot; with AMD Ryzen 5 and Vega 8 graphics.  I&#39;ll get into why another time but one of the things that didn&#39;t work quite well had to do with the laptop freezing every once in a while. It seemed random at first but some searching revealed that adding a kernel parameter solves the issue. That kernel param is &lt;code&gt;idle=nomwait&lt;/code&gt;. Since it was successful in stopping the freezing, I thought I&#39;d make it permanent. Here&#39;s how:&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChromeOS Shortcomings</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-26-chromeos-shortcomings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:09:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-26-chromeos-shortcomings/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using ChromeOS as my main development machine for a while now. At first I logged in under my personal gmail and used Crouton for development, but after Crostini I decided to separate out my work and personal items. Here are a few things that still bother me and why I might go back to a full linux environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multiple-users---sign-out&#34;&gt;Multiple Users - sign out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two major problems with multiple users on Chrome. The first is that once you sign in another user, you can&#39;t just sign them out. You have to sign out ALL users. This is incredibly annoying because of resources taken keeping another user signed in but also because of the lock screen privacy (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinstall a broken MySQL 5.7 Ubuntu Xenial</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-31-fix-broken-mysql-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 10:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-31-fix-broken-mysql-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed that particularly in Ubuntu Xenial, an apt-upgrade to mysql 5.7 fails. A standard re-install doesn&#39;t work for me so I&#39;ve resorted to more extreme methods to get my install working. This is only suitable for development, mind you. Please do not attempt in production without full backups and supervision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Setting up mysql-server-5.7 (5.7.12-0ubuntu1) ...
Job for mysql.service failed because the control process exited with error code. See &#34;systemctl status mysql.service&#34; and &#34;journalctl -xe&#34; for details.
invoke-rc.d: initscript mysql, action &#34;start&#34; failed.
dpkg: error processing package mysql-server-5.7 (--configure):
 subprocess installed post-installation script returned error exit status 1
 Errors were encountered while processing:
  mysql-server-5.7
  E: Sub-process /usr/bin/dpkg returned an error code (1)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to remove and reinstall also fails. The only solution I&#39;ve found so far is to completely purge MySQL and reinstall it from scratch. I&#39;m sure you can tweak these instructions to backup and restore your data. Maybe if I swtich back from Postgres I&#39;ll be motivated to look that up but for now, restoring the one db that uses MySQL is pretty easy. So what&#39;s the process?&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip: Set up a Reverse SSH Tunnel</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-06-10-reverse-ssh-tunnel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-06-10-reverse-ssh-tunnel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Often times I find myself using ssh to get to a server in order to get a file. The problem is that my local machine doesn&#39;t have its own publicly accessible IP address. So I end up ssh&#39;ing into the remote server, creating the file I need (e.g. database backup) and then exiting only to run scp from my local machine afterwards. Plus, if after that I want to erase the file on the remote server I have to ssh in again and tidy up after myself. That&#39;s me running ssh x2 and scp x1 every time I want to accomplish what should be simple. There&#39;s got to be an easier way, right? You bet..&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swapping Control &amp; Alt in Linux</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-04-19-swap-control-alt-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-04-19-swap-control-alt-linux/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;More for my own reference and in preparation of me completely gutting my system, I&#39;m posting the contents of my .xmodmaprc file which swaps the left control and alt-keys. This allows me to use my linux laptop more like I used my mac, with the command key. Many distributions now let you swap this from a setting but if yours doesn&#39;t here is how to go about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to copy the contents to a file called .xmodmaprc and run it using the xmodmap command:&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip: Sort by directory size in linux</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-02-14-sort-by-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-02-14-sort-by-directory/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve got files hidden around your system and you don&#39;t know where they are, you can use a quick command to track them down and sort them with the largest first. Handy when trying to prune your old files or free up space on your hard disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo du --max-depth=1 /home/ | sort -n -rs
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Things I Love About ArchLinux</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2007-05-31-ten-things-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 10:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2007-05-31-ten-things-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been back on Mac OSX for over a year now, using it for all my daily activities from email and web surfing to programming and device syncing. Something has been eating at me though and I find myself pining for my old linux desktop. Since buying a new rig for kicks is out of the question, I instead dug up a beat up IBM T22 and grabbed my Kubuntu Alternative Install CD and went to it.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
