<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Archlinux on Greycloak</title><link>https://greycloak.com/tags/archlinux/</link><description>Recent content in Archlinux on Greycloak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Vince Wadhwani; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greycloak.com/tags/archlinux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Rmagick 3.1 on Archlinux</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-04-16-rmagick-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-04-16-rmagick-arch-linux/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;So you're doing ruby development in 2019, eh? Good for you! Despite the rumors, Ruby on Rails is still a great way to get a project up and running. I managed to get the core of &lt;a href="https://www.rpgbuddy.com"&gt;https://www.rpgbuddy.com&lt;/a&gt; up and running in a week. One of my clients is also still running Ruby and I need to upgrade them from an old 2.3.3 version to 2.6.2. With that I decided to update a bunch of old gems too. One of those is Rmagick.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Giving Archlinux Another Try</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-01-29-giving-arch-another-try/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-01-29-giving-arch-another-try/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;I bought an HP Envy x360 a few months ago. It had the right combination of features I wanted. Touchscreen, 360 flip, smaller screen size, and decent graphics chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was I wanted to draw, read, and play games on a computer while running linux. Shouldn't be that hard to do but surpringly, any computers that have a touch screen and can flip are either too big to read on comfortably or have a lousy intel chip.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ten Things I Love About ArchLinux</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2007-05-31-ten-things-archlinux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 10:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2007-05-31-ten-things-archlinux/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been back on Mac OSX for over a year now, using it for all my daily activities from email and web surfing to programming and device syncing. Something has been eating at me though and I find myself pining for my old linux desktop. Since buying a new rig for kicks is out of the question, I instead dug up a beat up IBM T22 and grabbed my Kubuntu Alternative Install CD and went to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>