<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tutorial on Greycloak</title><link>https://greycloak.com/categories/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in tutorial on Greycloak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greycloak.com/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Make Firefox address bar work like Chrome</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-11-19-firefox-address-bar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-11-19-firefox-address-bar/</guid><description>
I've been using Firefox as my main browser for a few years now. I like supporting an independent organization and have come to really appreciate the containers functionality which helps me segragate activity. One gripe I've had is that I much prefer the way Google Chrome handle's URL completion. When I'm in Chrome and I type d it automatically autocompletes to https://www.discord.com/app in the address bar.
By contrast, in Firefox typing the same thing autocompletes to https://www.</description></item><item><title>Install Rmagick 3.1 on Archlinux</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-04-16-rmagick-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-04-16-rmagick-arch-linux/</guid><description>
So you're doing ruby development in 2019, eh? Good for you! Despite the rumors, Ruby on Rails is still a great way to get a project up and running. I managed to get the core of https://www.rpgbuddy.com up and running in a week. One of my clients is also still running Ruby and I need to upgrade them from an old 2.3.3 version to 2.6.2. With that I decided to update a bunch of old gems too.</description></item><item><title>Should you npm install globally?</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-22-should-you-npm-install-globally/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-22-should-you-npm-install-globally/</guid><description>
I was transitioning this blog from using Jekyll to Hexo. After comparing both, I feel I made the right choice. However, I almost started off on the wrong foot. Being unfamiliar with Node.js, I was reviewing the Hexo install instructions and the first thing it tells you is to install via:
1npm install hexo-cli -g I'm running on Archlinux and got a permission denied error when I tried that. It's likely because I used pacman (the Archlinux package manager) to install node and/or npm.</description></item><item><title>Getting touchscreen events working with Firefox</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-01-firefox-with-touch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-02-01-firefox-with-touch/</guid><description>
I bought this laptop with a touchscreen and occasionally find myself using it while surfing websites. Now with Chrome that worked just fine but with Firefox it tends to select areas of text instead of scrolling. That sucks!
Fortunately it's quite fixable. You just have to modify the .desktop file (or launch from the command line) with an additional environmental option: env MOZ_USE_XINPUT2=1
On most linux distributions, the .desktop file is in /usr/local/share/applications or ~/.</description></item><item><title>Install MariaDB in Debian Stretch</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-12-21-install-mariadb-debian/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-12-21-install-mariadb-debian/</guid><description>
Note that this article for local installation of Maria DB or MySQL. It's intended to help you get up and running with the database locally and is not intended as a production tutorial. If you need to use either in a production environment, please contact a professional.
Step 1: update and install
1sudo apt update 2sudo apt upgrade 3sudo apt install mariadb-server mariadb-client Step 2: (Optional) Run the secure installation. Doesn't hurt to see the options for future reference.</description></item><item><title>Patch the Ubuntu Kernel</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-11-01-patch-ubuntu-kernel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-11-01-patch-ubuntu-kernel/</guid><description>
I bought an HP Envy x360 and out of the box it works pretty well with linux. I've got Ubuntu 18.10 installed and have only had to tweak a couple of minor things. There is however, one big problem and that is the touch screen doesn't work. It might be the HP firmware (I am still figuring out how to update it in linux) but in the meantime, there is a patch available.</description></item><item><title>Fix Occasional Freezing on the HP Envy X360</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-31-fix-freezing-envyx360/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 10:09:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-31-fix-freezing-envyx360/</guid><description>
01/2019 update: This doesn't seem to be necessary with the 4.20 kernel!
I recently bought an HP Envy x360 13&amp;quot; with AMD Ryzen 5 and Vega 8 graphics. I'll get into why another time but one of the things that didn't work quite well had to do with the laptop freezing every once in a while. It seemed random at first but some searching revealed that adding a kernel parameter solves the issue.</description></item><item><title>Reinstall a broken MySQL 5.7 Ubuntu Xenial</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-31-fix-broken-mysql-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 10:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-31-fix-broken-mysql-ubuntu/</guid><description>
I've noticed that particularly in Ubuntu Xenial, an apt-upgrade to mysql 5.7 fails. A standard re-install doesn't work for me so I've resorted to more extreme methods to get my install working. This is only suitable for development, mind you. Please do not attempt in production without full backups and supervision.
Error:
Setting up mysql-server-5.7 (5.7.12-0ubuntu1) ... Job for mysql.service failed because the control process exited with error code. See "</description></item><item><title>Fixing keyboard and mouse lag in Xorg (crouton)</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-07-fix-keyboard-lag-crouton/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 03:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-07-fix-keyboard-lag-crouton/</guid><description>
I've been using a Chromebook for development lately. On the side, I like to load up games and play using the linux installation I have loaded up via Crouton. Crouton is amazing and what we'll be using until native linux comes baked in, but it has some issues. There are a number of &amp;quot;targets&amp;quot; for displaying a desktop environment including xiwi and xorg. Here, I'll discuss those two targets and tell you how to fix performance in the latter.</description></item><item><title>Setting up PostgreSQL on Debian Buster</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-07-debian-postgresql-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 03:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-07-debian-postgresql-setup/</guid><description>
In a previous article, we set up your Debian Buster system with git, ruby, and a bash shell that tells you the ruby version and branch. Next up, we're going to install PostgreSQL and dependencies needed to get it working with Ruby on Rails.
First, let's make sure your system is up to date:
1sudo apt update 2sudo apt upgrade Next, we're going to jump right in and install postgres 10:</description></item><item><title>Setting up Debian Buster for Ruby Development</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-06-debian-ruby-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-07-06-debian-ruby-setup/</guid><description>
So you've got a new debian install and need to get it set up to do real work? Here's a quick guide to get the packages you need assuming you're using Debian's current testing distro, Buster, installed.
First, let's make sure your system is up to date:
1sudo apt update 2sudo apt upgrade Next, let's grab the essentials including git:
1sudo apt install git curl zlib1g-dev build-essential libssl-dev libreadline-dev libyaml-dev libsqlite3-dev sqlite3 libxml2-dev libxslt1-dev libcurl4-openssl-dev software-properties-common libffi-dev nodejs Before we get too far, let's configure git.</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip: Exporting to CSV from Rails console</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2013-10-08-export-rails-to-csv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 10:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2013-10-08-export-rails-to-csv/</guid><description>
This is an ugly solution but one that can come in handy if you just need to get some sample data out of your rails application. My particular use case was exporting data from various tables into a CSV file so I could use a 3rd party email service. We have users in a multi-tenant app so it's not quite so simple as just exporting a single table. This is something you almost certainly don't need to use if your SQL-fu is strong.</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip: Set up a Reverse SSH Tunnel</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-06-10-reverse-ssh-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-06-10-reverse-ssh-tunnel/</guid><description>
Often times I find myself using ssh to get to a server in order to get a file. The problem is that my local machine doesn't have its own publicly accessible IP address. So I end up ssh'ing into the remote server, creating the file I need (e.g. database backup) and then exiting only to run scp from my local machine afterwards. Plus, if after that I want to erase the file on the remote server I have to ssh in again and tidy up after myself.</description></item><item><title>Swapping Control &amp; Alt in Linux</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-04-19-swap-control-alt-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-04-19-swap-control-alt-linux/</guid><description>
More for my own reference and in preparation of me completely gutting my system, I'm posting the contents of my .xmodmaprc file which swaps the left control and alt-keys. This allows me to use my linux laptop more like I used my mac, with the command key. Many distributions now let you swap this from a setting but if yours doesn't here is how to go about it.
Feel free to copy the contents to a file called .</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip: Sort by directory size in linux</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-02-14-sort-by-directory/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 23:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2009-02-14-sort-by-directory/</guid><description>
If you've got files hidden around your system and you don't know where they are, you can use a quick command to track them down and sort them with the largest first. Handy when trying to prune your old files or free up space on your hard disk.
Try this:
1sudo du --max-depth=1 /home/ | sort -n -rs</description></item></channel></rss>