<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>raspberrypi on Greycloak</title><link>https://greycloak.com/tags/raspberrypi/</link><description>Recent content in raspberrypi on Greycloak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Vince Wadhwani; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greycloak.com/tags/raspberrypi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Headless SSD install on Raspberry Pi 4B</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2023-01-26-headless-ssd-install-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2023-01-26-headless-ssd-install-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>
I have a Raspberry Pi 4B that I use as a mini home server and pi-hole. I love that I can block intrusive ads, have a secure vpn connection to my home network, and have backup for my music collection. The Raspberry Pi 4 is a fun little device and if you can get your hands on one, it has a lot of cool uses. (Note, if you're having trouble, may I recommend RPILocator.</description></item><item><title>Free Dynamic DNS with Namecheap for Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-12-30-dynamic-dns-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-12-30-dynamic-dns-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>
I've got a PiHole set up on my raspberry pi and have it connected to my home router. My ISP won't assign me a static IP address though it's pretty good about keeping the one I've got active until I reboot my router. For the most part that's been good enough for me but I wanted to finally get dynamic dns going so I wouldn't have to worry about it again.</description></item><item><title>Joplin CLI on Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-08-05-joplin-cli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-08-05-joplin-cli/</guid><description>
I've been searching for a way to keep my notes and todos organized. Over the years I've tried some interesting solutions like Evernote, Google Tasks, and even Task Warrior. All of them have their pros and cons but I've recently really liked the flexibility and ease of use of Joplin.
The screenshots will show you that it's got a complete Graphical User Interface and is usable across most operating systems including Linux so if you want to do that, by all means check it out.</description></item></channel></rss>