<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Greycloak</title>
    <link>https://greycloak.com/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Greycloak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 12:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greycloak.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Cassette Culture</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-05-01-benefits-cassette-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2022-05-01-benefits-cassette-culture/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m GenX and I grew up on a budget. That meant listening to the radio and trying to record my favorite song onto a cassette tape so I could listen to it in my parent&#39;s car or on a cheap portable cassette player on the way to school. When CD&#39;s came on the scene, like many others, I jumped on board eager to get perfect sound quality and leave behind clumsy track skipping.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Archlinux Another Try</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-01-29-giving-arch-another-try/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 16:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2019-01-29-giving-arch-another-try/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I bought an HP Envy x360 a few months ago. It had the right combination of features I wanted. Touchscreen, 360 flip, smaller screen size, and decent graphics chip.
The plan was I wanted to draw, read, and play games on a computer while running linux. Shouldn&#39;t be that hard to do but surpringly, any computers that have a touch screen and can flip are either too big to read on comfortably or have a lousy intel chip.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChromeOS Shortcomings</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-26-chromeos-shortcomings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:09:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2018-10-26-chromeos-shortcomings/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been using ChromeOS as my main development machine for a while now. At first I logged in under my personal gmail and used Crouton for development, but after Crostini I decided to separate out my work and personal items. Here are a few things that still bother me and why I might go back to a full linux environment:
Multiple Users - sign out There are two major problems with multiple users on Chrome.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Things I Love About ArchLinux</title>
      <link>https://greycloak.com/post/2007-05-31-ten-things-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 10:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greycloak.com/post/2007-05-31-ten-things-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been back on Mac OSX for over a year now, using it for all my daily activities from email and web surfing to programming and device syncing. Something has been eating at me though and I find myself pining for my old linux desktop. Since buying a new rig for kicks is out of the question, I instead dug up a beat up IBM T22 and grabbed my Kubuntu Alternative Install CD and went to it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
